Guide to the Laura McPhee River of No Return Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
River of No Return Collection
2003-2014
WA Photos 591
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
40.0
(41 boxes)
The River of No Return Collection consists of photographs created by Laura McPhee that document sites and persons in the Sawtooth Valley of Idaho, 2003-2008, related to her work as the initial Artist in Residence in the area underwritten by the Alturas Foundation, as well as project files, 2003-2014, which contain material related imagery and products from the project, including a solo exhibition at the Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, in 2006, and her book, River of No Return (New Haven, Connecticut: Yale University Press, 2009). Photographic material in the collection includes color and black-and-white photographic prints, transparencies, and film negatives. Project files include research, correspondence, and print lists as well as preparatory and promotion material related to exhibitions of her images and production of her book.
McPhee, Laura
Content Description
The River of No Return Collection consists of photographs created by Laura McPhee that document sites and persons in the Sawtooth Valley of Idaho, 2003-2008, related to her work as the initial Artist in Residence in the area underwritten by the Alturas Foundation, as well as project files, 2003-2014, which contain material related imagery and products from the project, including a solo exhibition at the Museum of Fine Arts, Boston, in 2006, and her book, River of No Return (New Haven, Connecticut: Yale University Press, 2009). Photographic material in the collection consists of approximately 2000 items including color and black-and-white photographic prints, transparencies, and film negatives. Project files include research, correspondence, and print lists as well as the artist's maquette for River of No Return and multiple dummies reflecting the design evolution of the book. The collection also includes preparatory and promotional material related to exhibitions of her images.
Exterior images document sites in the Sawtooth Valley in the Sawtooth National Recreation Area of the Sawtooth National Forest, which encompasses portions of Blaine County and Custer County in central Idaho as well as the communities of Custer and Stanley.
Landscape photographs include views of the White Cloud Peaks as well as bodies of water and their surrounding areas including Alturas Lake, Champion Creek, Fisher Creek, Fourth of July Creek, Little Redfish Lake, Lost Creek, Pettit Lake, Redfish Lake Creek, Salmon River (also known as the River of No Return), Stanley Lake, and Valley Creek.
Ranches represented in imagery include Fourth of July Creek Ranch, H-Hook Ranch, Laverty Ranch, and Morgan Williams Ranch.
Enterprises documented in photographs include the Sawtooth Fish Hatchery operated by the Idaho Department of Fish and Game near Stanley, the Grouse Creek Mine operated by the Hecla Mining Company in Custer, the Three Rivers Stone Quarry in Clayton, and deserted mines in Custer including the Bayhorse Lead-Silver Mine and the Clayton Silver Mine.
Discrete groups of images document forest fires in the region as well as fishing and hunting activities. The latter include the butchering of a harvested elk and examples of illegally harvested mammals, birds, and fish confiscated by the Idaho Department of Fish and Game.
Individuals with formal and informal portraits in the collection include Mark Anderson, Isaac Babcock, Robert G. Griswold, Mattie Griswold, Judy Ann Hall-Griswold, Matt Humphreys, Isobel McPhee, Gamaniel Tacza, Tom Thurber, and Rob Trahant.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Laura McPhee on the Frederick W. and Carrie S. Beinecke Fund for Western Americana, 2017.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: I. Photographic Material, 2003-2008. II. Project Files, 2003-2014.
Related Materials
Laura McPhee Photographs of the American West (WA Photos Folio 152). Yale Collection of Western Americana, Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library.
Laura McPhee (born 1958)
Laura McPhee is a photographer. Born in New York City and raised in central New Jersey, she earned a Bachelor of Arts in Art History from Princeton University in 1980, and a Master of Fine Arts in Photography from the Rhode Island School of Design in 1986. Her work, which ranges from portrait to landscape to still life, is widely exhibited nationally and internationally. She has been a member of the faculty at the Massachusetts College of Art and Design since 1986 and lives in Brookline, Massachusetts.
Bodies of water -- Idaho -- Sawtooth Valley -- Pictorial works; Landscape photographs -- Idaho -- Pictorial works; Blaine County (Idaho) -- Pictorial works; Clayton (Idaho) -- Pictorial works; Custer (Idaho) -- Pictorial works; Custer County (Idaho) -- Pictorial works; Idaho -- Pictorial works; Sawtooth National Forest (Idaho and Utah) -- Pictorial works; Sawtooth National Recreation Area (Idaho) -- Pictorial works; Sawtooth Valley (Idaho) -- Pictorial works; Stanley (Idaho) -- Pictorial works; White Cloud Peaks (Idaho) -- Pictorial works; Black-and-white prints (photographs); Chromogenic color prints; Color negatives; Dummies (Printed matter); Inkjet prints; Negatives (photographs); Photographs; Transparencies; McPhee, Laura; McPhee, Laura; Alturas Foundation; Idaho. Fish and Game Department -- Pictorial works; Museum of Fine Arts, Boston -- Exhibitions
- Photographic Material, 2003–2008; Series I
  Arrangement
  Series I is organized into four subseries: Oversize Prints, Work Prints, Color Transparencies, and Negatives.
  - Oversize Prints, 2006–2008
    Scope and Contents
    Photographic material created by Laura McPhee that documents sites and individuals in the Sawtooth Valley, Idaho, 2003-2008. Material includes oversize color photographic prints, color and black-and-white photographic work prints, transparencies, and film negatives, 2003-2008.
    Organized under three headings: Chromogenic Color Prints, 51 x 61 cm, Inkjet prints, 44 x 56 cm, and Chromogenic Color Prints, 28 x 35.5 cm.
    - Chromogenic Color Prints, 51 x 61 cm, 2006–2007
      Arranged sequentially by negative number.
      - Untitled, 2005 (Negative Number 632), 2006–2007 (Box 1 (Oversize), Folder 1)
      - Untitled, 2005 (Negative Number 638), 2006–2007 (Box 1 (Oversize), Folder 2)
      - Depression Glass (Made with Uranium) and Fluorite Under a Black Light, Sawtooth City, Idaho, 2005 (Negative Number 641), 2006–2007 (Box 1 (Oversize), Folder 3)
      - Igloo Built From Downloaded Plans, Park Creek Custer County, Idaho, 2005 (Negative Number 643), 2006–2007 (Box 1 (Oversize), Folder 4)
      - Untitled, 2005 (Negative Number 644), 2006–2007 (Box 1 (Oversize), Folder 5)
      - Bob Cutting Ice, Stanley Lake, Custer County, Idaho, 2005 (Negative Number 650), 2006–2007 (Box 1 (Oversize), Folder 6)
      - Illegally Kept Snake River Chinook Salmon with Freezer Burn, Custer County, Idaho, 2005 (Negative Number 658), 2006–2007 (Box 1 (Oversize), Folder 7)
      - Untitled, 2005 (Negative Number 666), 2006–2007 (Box 1 (Oversize), Folder 8)
      - Untitled, 2005 (Negative Number 668), 2006–2007 (Box 1 (Oversize), Folder 9)
      - Fox Confiscated from a Leghold Trap at Rough Creek, Custer County, Idaho, 2005 (Negative Number 673), 2006–2007 (Box 1 (Oversize), Folder 10)
      - Untitled, 2005 (Negative Number 681), 2006–2007 (Box 1 (Oversize), Folder 11)
      - Air Bladder of an Endangered Sockeye Salmon, Pettit Lake, Blaine County, Idaho, 2005 (Negative Number 686), 2006–2007 (Box 1 (Oversize), Folder 12)
      - Fly Line for Steelhead, Robinson Bar, Salmon River, Custer County, Idaho, 2005 (Negative Number 689), 2006–2007 (Box 1 (Oversize), Folder 13)
      - Untitled, 2005 (Negative Number 690), 2006–2007 (Box 1 (Oversize), Folder 14)
      - Untitled, 2005 (Negative Number 695), 2006–2007 (Box 1 (Oversize), Folder 15)
      - Tire Swing, Alturas Lake, Blaine County, Idaho, 2005 (Negative Number 710), 2006–2007 (Box 1 (Oversize), Folder 16)
      - One Car Passing, Valley Road, Sawtooth Valley, Idaho, 2003 (Negative Number 1520), 2006–2007 (Box 1 (Oversize), Folder 17)
      - Cyanide Evaporation Pool by the River of No Return Wilderness, Grouse Creek Lead, Silver and Gold Mine, Yankee Fork, Idaho, 2005 (Negative Number 2073), 2006–2007 (Box 1 (Oversize), Folder 18)
      - Mattie, Bob, and Bo, Road Creek, Custer County, Idaho, 2005 (Negative Number 2095), 2006–2007 (Box 1 (Oversize), Folder 19)
      - Mattie in Her Grandmother's Wedding Dress, Laverty Ranch, Custer County, Idaho, May 2005 (Negative Number 2097), 2006–2007 (Box 1 (Oversize), Folder 20)
      - Mattie with a Northern Red-Shafted Flicker in Her Eighth Grade Graduation Dress, Laverty Ranch, Idaho, March 2005 (Negative Number 2099), 2006–2007 (Box 2 (Oversize), Folder 21)
      - Lodgepole Pines Killed by Beetles, Nip and Tuck Road, Custer County, Idaho, 2005 (Negative Number 2106), 2006–2007 (Box 2 (Oversize), Folder 22)
      - Untitled, 2005 (Negative Number 2124), 2006–2007 (Box 2 (Oversize), Folder 23)
      - Mattie in Her Eighth Grade Graduation Dress Holding a Robin's Nest, Laverty Ranch, Custer County, Idaho, May 2005 (Negative Number 2148), 2006–2007 (Box 2 (Oversize), Folder 24)
      - Judy with Elk Heart, H-Hook Ranch, Custer County, Idaho, 2004 (Negative Number 2912), 2006–2007 (Box 2 (Oversize), Folder 25)
      - Alturas Lake Outlet, Blaine County, Idaho, 2004 (Negative Number 2922), 2006-2007 (Box 2 (Oversize), Folder 26)
      - Alturas Lake Outlet, Blaine County, Idaho, 2004 (Negative Number 2929), 2006–2007 (Box 2 (Oversize), Folder 27)
      - Chest Cavity, Rocky Mountain Cow Elk, Custer County, Idaho, 2004 (Negative Number 2941), 2006–2007 (Box 2 (Oversize), Folder 28)
      - Skinned Elk, White Cloud Mountains, Idaho, 2004 (Negative Number 2943), 2006–2007 (Box 2 (Oversize), Folder 29)
      - Untitled, 2004 (Negative Number 2951), 2006–2007 (Box 2 (Oversize), Folder 30)
      - Mattie with a Bourbon Red Turkey, Laverty Ranch, Custer County, Idaho, 2004 (Negative Number 2970), 2006–2007 (Box 2 (Oversize), Folder 31)
      - Untitled, 2004 (Negative Number 2999), 2006–2007 (Box 2 (Oversize), Folder 32)
      - Untitled, 2004 (Negative Number 3003), 2006–2007 (Box 2 (Oversize), Folder 33)
      - Untitled, 2004 (Negative Number 3006), 2006–2007 (Box 2 (Oversize), Folder 34)
      - Burned Timber, Fourth of July Creek, Valley Road Wildfire, Custer County, Idaho, 2005 (Negative Number 3676), 2006–2007 (Box 2 (Oversize), Folder 35)
      - Untitled, 2005 (Negative Number 3678), 2006–2007 (Box 2 (Oversize), Folder 36)
      - Smoke from a Wildfire Ignited by Sparks from a Burn Barrel, Champion Creek, Custer County, Idaho, 2005 (Negative Number 3687), 2006–2007 (Box 2 (Oversize), Folder 37)
      - Understory Flareups, Fourth of July Creek, Valley Road Wildfire, Custer County, Idaho, 2005 (Negative Number 3698), 2006–2007 (Box 2 (Oversize), Folder 38)
      - Smoke Above Fisher Creek, Valley Road Wildfire, 40,838 Acres Burned, Custer County, Idaho, 2005 (Negative Number 3703), 2006–2007 (Box 2 (Oversize), Folder 39)
      - Matt Visiting Shepherd's Camp Near Lost Creek, Custer County, Idaho, 2003 (Negative Number 5965), 2006–2007 (Box 2 (Oversize), Folder 40)
      - Gamaniel Tacza, Peruvian Sheperd, Fourth of July Creek, White Cloud Mountains, Idaho, 2003 (Negative Number 6048), 2006–2007 (Box 3 (Oversize), Folder 41)
      - Untitled, 2003 (Negative Number 6116), 2006–2007 (Box 3 (Oversize), Folder 42)
      - Nineteen-twenties Settler's Cabin at the Edge of a Subdivision, Sawtooth Valley, Idaho, 2003 (Negative Number 6254), 2006–2007 (Box 3 (Oversize), Folder 43)
      - Untitled, 2004 (Negative Number 6340), 2006–2007 (Box 3 (Oversize), Folder 44)
      - Irrigator's Tarp Directing Water, Fourth of July Creek Ranch, Custer County, Idaho, 2004 (Negative Number 6341), 2006–2007 (Box 3 (Oversize), Folder 45)
      - Salvage, Custer County Transfer Station, Stanley, Idaho, 2004 (Negative Number 6345), 2006–2007 (Box 3 (Oversize), Folder 46)
      - Nineteen-Seventies Magazine, Old Obsidian, Idaho, 2004 (Negative Number 6349), 2006–2007 (Box 3 (Oversize), Folder 47)
      - Untitled, 2004 (Negative Number 6350), 2006–2007 (Box 3 (Oversize), Folder 48)
      - Isobel, Fourth of July Creek Ranch, Custer County, Idaho, 2004 (Negative Number 6356), 2006–2007 (Box 3 (Oversize), Folder 49)
      - Fourth of July Creek Ranch, Custer County, Idaho, July 15, 2004 (Negative Number 6380), 2006–2007 (Box 3 (Oversize), Folder 50)
      - Untitled, 2004 (Negative Number 6383), 2006–2007 (Box 3 (Oversize), Folder 51)
      - Mattie with a Plymouth Barred Rock Hen, Laverty Ranch, Custer County, Idaho, 2004 (Negative Number 6471), 2006–2007 (Box 3 (Oversize), Folder 52)
      - Rob Trahant, Shoshone-Bannock Tribal Member, Counting Fish for Juvenile Chinook Salmon Survey, Valley Creek, Custer County, Idaho, 2004 (Negative Number 6484), 2006–2007 (Box 3 (Oversize), Folder 53)
      - Angler's Path Among Willows, Valley Creek, Custer County, Idaho, 2004 (Negative Number 6492), 2006–2007 (Box 3 (Oversize), Folder 54)
      - Cascade, Redfish Lake Creek, Sawtooth Wilderness, Idaho, 2004 (Negative Number 6494), 2006–2007 (Box 3 (Oversize), Folder 55)
      - Fourth of July Creek Ranch, Custer County, Idaho, June 21, 2003 (Negative Number 6542), 2006–2007 (Box 3 (Oversize), Folder 56)
      - Aspens Carved by Sheep Herders, Fisher Creek, White Cloud Mountains, Idaho, Summer Solstice, 2003 (Negative Number 6548), 2006–2007 (Box 3 (Oversize), Folder 57)
      - Rocks from Sawtooth National Forest for Landscaping in Sun Valley, Pettit Lake Road, Blaine County, Idaho, 2003 (Negative Number 6575), 2006–2007 (Box 3 (Oversize), Folder 58)
      - Untitled, 2003 (Negative Number 6580), 2006–2007 (Box 3 (Oversize), Folder 59)
      - Untitled, 2003 (Negative Number 6583), 2006–2007 (Box 3 (Oversize), Folder 60)
      - Fourth of July Ranch, Custer County, Idaho, July 8, 2004 (Negative Number 6584), 2006–2007 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 61)
      - Judy Tracking Radio-Collared Wolves From Her Yard, Summer Range, H-Hook Ranch Custer County, Idaho, 2004 (Negative Number 6585), 2006–2007 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 62)
      - Untitled, 2003 (Negative Number 6586), 2006–2007 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 63)
      - Untitled, 2003 (Negative Number 6598), 2006–2007 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 64)
      - Tom Thurber Cutting Firewood, Lost Creek, Custer County, Idaho, 2003 (Negative Number 7761), 2006–2007 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 65)
      - Little Redfish Lake Campground, Custer County, Idaho, 2003 (Negative Number 7821), 2006–2007 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 66)
      - Red Fladry to Spook Wolves and Deter Them from Killing Claves, Fourth of July Creek Ranch, Custer County, Idaho, September 30, 2003 (Negative Number 7864), 2006–2007 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 67)
      - Untitled, 2003 (Negative Number 7894), 2006–2007 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 68)
      - Isaac Babcock, Biologist for the Nez Pierce Tribe, Dressed for Tranquilizing and Radio-Collaring Wolves, Fourth of July Creek, Custer County, Idaho, 2003 (Negative Number 8028), 2006–2007 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 69)
      - Mark Anderson Panning for Gold in 19th Century Tailings, Joe's Gulch, Lower Stanley, Idaho, 2003 (Negative Number 8033), 2006–2007 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 70)
      - Sorting Black Angus Cow/Calf Pairs, Morgan Williams Ranch, Custer County, Idaho, 2003 (Negative Number 8043), 2006–2007 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 71)
      - Breached Dam at Sunbeam on the Salmon River, Custer County, Idaho, 2003 (Negative Number 8060), 2006–2007 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 72)
      - Untitled, 2004 (Negative Number 9555), 2006–2007 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 73)
      - Untitled, 2004 (Negative Number 9561), 2006–2007 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 74)
      - Mattie, Fisher Creek Turnout, Challis School District, Idaho, 2004 (Negative Number 9573), 2006–2007 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 75)
      - Untitled, 2004 (Negative Number 9637), 2006–2007 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 76)
      - Untitled, 2004 (Negative Number 9640), 2006–2007 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 77)
      - Sawtooth Range, Custer County, Idaho, 2004 (Negative Number 9641, 2006–2007 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 78)
      - Campfire, H-Hook Ranch, Custer County, Idaho, 2004 (Negative Number 9745), 2006–2007 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 79)
      - Endangered Sockeye Salmon Fry, Main Vat Room, Sawtooth Fish Hatchery, Custer County, Idaho, 2004 (Negative Number 9753), 2006–2007 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 80)
      - Untitled, 2004 (Negative Number 9787), 2006–2007 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 81)
      - Untitled, 2007-2008 (Negative Number 92854), 2006–2007 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 82)
      - Untitled, 2007-2008 (Negative Number 94082), 2006–2007 (Box 4 (Oversize), Folder 83)
    - Inkjet Prints, 44 x 56 cm, 2006–2007
      - Igloo Built From Downloaded Plans, Park Creek Custer County, Idaho, 2005 (Negative Number 643), 2006–2007 (Box 5 (Oversize), Folder 84)
      - Illegally Kept Snake River Chinook Salmon with Freezer Burn, Custer County, Idaho, 2005 (Negative Number 658), 2006–2007 (Box 5 (Oversize), Folder 85)
      - Untitled, 2005 (Negative Number 666), 2006–2007 (Box 5 (Oversize), Folder 86)
      - Untitled, 2005 (Negative Number 668), 2006–2007 (Box 5 (Oversize), Folder 87)
      - Untitled, 2005 (Negative Number 670), 2006–2007 (Box 5 (Oversize), Folder 88)
      - Fox Confiscated from a Leghold Trap at Rough Creek, Custer County, Idaho, 2005 (Negative Number 673), 2006–2007 (Box 5 (Oversize), Folder 89)
      - Untitled, 2005 (Negative Number 681), 2006–2007 (Box 5 (Oversize), Folder 90)
      - Cyanide Evaporation Pool by the River of No Return Wilderness, Grouse Creek Lead, Silver and Gold Mine, Yankee Fork, Idaho, 2005 (Negative Number 2073), 2006–2007 (Box 5 (Oversize), Folder 91)
      - Mattie, Bob, and Bo, Road Creek, Custer County, Idaho, 2005 (Negative Number 2095), 2006–2007 (Box 5 (Oversize), Folder 92)
      - Untitled, 2005 (Negative Number 2104), 2006–2007 (Box 5 (Oversize), Folder 93)
      - Nineteen-forties Women's Magazines at the Manager's House at the Bayhorse Lead-Silver Mine, Custer County, Idaho, 2004 (Negative Number 2112), 2006–2007 (Box 5 (Oversize), Folder 94)
      - Untitled, 2005 (Negative Number 2142), 2006–2007 (Box 5 (Oversize), Folder 95)
      - Mattie in Her Eighth Grade Graduation Dress Holding a Robin's Nest, Laverty Ranch, Custer County, Idaho, May 2005 (Negative Number 2148), 2006–2007 (Box 5 (Oversize), Folder 96-97)
      - Untitled, 2005 (Negative Number 2524), 2006–2007 (Box 5 (Oversize), Folder 98)
      - Judy with Elk Heart, H-Hook Ranch, Custer County, Idaho, 2004 (Negative Number 2912), 2006–2007 (Box 5 (Oversize), Folder 99)
      - Untitled, 2004 (Negative Number 2925), 2006–2007 (Box 5 (Oversize), Folder 100)
      - Quatered Rocky Mountain Elk, Milky Creek, White Cloud Mountains, Idaho, 2004 (Negative Number 2929), 2006–2007 (Box 5 (Oversize), Folder 101)
      - Chest Cavity, Rocky Mountain Cow Elk, Custer County, Idaho, 2004 (Negative Number 2941), 2006–2007 (Box 5 (Oversize), Folder 102)
      - Untitled, 2004 (Negative Number 2981), 2006–2007 (Box 5 (Oversize), Folder 103)
      - Floating Dock Beached for Winter, Alturas Lake, Blaine County, Idaho, 2004 (Negative Number 2993), 2006–2007 (Box 6 (Oversize), Folder 104)
      - Burned Timber, Fourth of July Creek, Valley Road Wildfire, Custer County, Idaho, 2005 (Negative Number 3676), 2006–2007 (Box 6 (Oversize), Folder 105)
      - Untitled, 2005 (Negative Number 3686?), 2006–2007 (Box 6 (Oversize), Folder 106)
        Negative not extant
      - Untitled, 2005 (Negative Number 3709), 2006–2007 (Box 6 (Oversize), Folder 107)
      - Gamaniel Tacza, Peruvian Sheperd, Fourth of July Creek, White Cloud Mountains, Idaho, 2003 (Negative Number 6048), 2006–2007 (Box 6 (Oversize), Folder 108)
      - Nineteen-twenties Settler's Cabin at the Edge of a Subdivision, Sawtooth Valley, Idaho, 2003 (Negative Number 6254), 2006–2007 (Box 6 (Oversize), Folder 109)
      - Untitled, 2004 (Negative Number 6340), 2006–2007 (Box 6 (Oversize), Folder 110)
      - Irrigator's Tarp Directing Water, Fourth of July Creek Ranch, Custer County, Idaho, 2004 (Negative Number 6341), 2006–2007 (Box 6 (Oversize), Folder 111-112)
      - Untitled, 2004 (Negative Number 6347), 2006–2007 (Box 6 (Oversize), Folder 113)
      - Isobel, Fourth of July Creek Ranch, Custer County, Idaho, 2004 (Negative Number 6356), 2006–2007 (Box 6 (Oversize), Folder 114)
      - Irrigation Ditch, Fourth of July Creek Ranch, Custer County, Idaho, 2004 (Negative Number 6379), 2006–2007 (Box 6 (Oversize), Folder 115)
      - Fourth of July Creek Ranch, Custer County, Idaho, July 15, 2004 (Negative Number 6380), 2006–2007 (Box 6 (Oversize), Folder 116)
      - Untitled, 2004 (Negative Number 6385), 2006–2007 (Box 6 (Oversize), Folder 117-118)
      - Untitled, 2004 (Negative Number 6391), 2006–2007 (Box 6 (Oversize), Folder 119)
      - Untitled, 2004 (Negative Number 6452), 2006–2007 (Box 6 (Oversize), Folder 120)
      - Fourth of July Creek Ranch, Custer County, Idaho, June 21, 2003 (Negative Number 6542), 2006–2007 (Box 6 (Oversize), Folder 121)
      - Aspens Carved by Sheep Herders, Fisher Creek, White Cloud Mountains, Idaho, Summer Solstice, 2003 (Negative Number 6548), 2006–2007 (Box 6 (Oversize), Folder 122)
      - Rocks from Sawtooth National Forest for Landscaping in Sun Valley, Pettit Lake Road, Blaine County, Idaho, 2003 (Negative Number 6575), 2006–2007 (Box 6 (Oversize), Folder 123)
      - Judy Tracking Radio-Collared Wolves From Her Yard, Summer Range, H-Hook Ranch Custer County, Idaho, 2004 (Negative Number 6585), 2006–2007 (Box 7 (Oversize), Folder 124)
      - Untitled, 2003 (Negative Number 7853), 2006–2007 (Box 7 (Oversize), Folder 125)
      - Isaac Babcock, Biologist for the Nez Pierce Tribe, Dressed for Tranquilizing and Radio-Collaring Wolves, Fourth of July Creek, Custer County, Idaho, 2003 (Negative Number 8028), 2006–2007 (Box 7 (Oversize), Folder 126)
      - Untitled, 2003 (Negative Number 8036), 2006–2007 (Box 7 (Oversize), Folder 127)
      - Breached Dam at Sunbeam on the Salmon River, Custer County, Idaho, 2003 (Negative Number 8060), 2006–2007 (Box 7 (Oversize), Folder 128)
      - Snowmobile Headlights, Valley Road, Custer County, Idaho, 2004 (Negative Number 9609), 2006–2007 (Box 7 (Oversize), Folder 129)
      - Campfire, H-Hook Ranch, Custer County, Idaho, 2004 (Negative Number 9745), 2006–2007 (Box 7 (Oversize), Folder 130)
      - Endangered Sockeye Salmon Fry, Main Vat Room, Sawtooth Fish Hatchery, Custer County, Idaho, 2004 (Negative Number 9753), 2006–2007 (Box 7 (Oversize), Folder 131)
    - Chromogenic Color Prints, 28 x 35.5 cm, 2008
      This material consists of chromogenic color prints on Kodak Professional Endura paper, 28 x 35.5 cm, which include includes incomplete sets of images published in Laura McPhee, River of No Return (New Haven, Connecticut: Yale University Press, 2009) as well as a set of images that did not appear in the work.
      Each folder in this component houses a single print except where noted.
      Organized under three headings: Book Proof Set, Book Proof Set, and Proofs Not Used in Book.
      - Book Proofs Set, 2008
        Lack prints for images published on pages 23, 71, and 87.
        Arrangement of prints mirrors the sequence that the images appeared in the book, Laura McPhee, River of No Return.
        - Irrigator's Tarp Directing Water, Fourth of July Creek Ranch, Custer County, Idaho, 2004 (Pages ii and 102, Negative Number 6341), 2008 (Box 8, Folder 132)
        - One Car Passing, Valley Road, Sawtooth Valley, Idaho, 2003 (Page 3, Negative Number 6584-1520), 2008 (Box 8, Folder 133)